PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name Bidhan Chandra Sutradhar

Mobile 01829600496

Email bidhanvk@gmail.com
Github https://gitlab.com/imbidhan
Website https://imbidhan.me



PERSONAL STATEMENT

Software developer professional with more than 3+ years of experience in designing and developing large-scale web and API based systems. Have moderate front-end development. Love to write clean code, follow best practices and apply modern reliable software engineering principles.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Syntech Solution Ltd Feb 2021 - Present

My Involvement as software Engineer:

- Analyze detailed product requirements.
- · Develop restful API for web and mobile app
- Experience with Service Oriented Architecture
- Developing some customizations.

Feature Project: Ministry of Agriculture, Ministry of social welfare, Ministry of Commerce all project developed: Laravel & vue Js following Micro service architecture.

- http://service.moa.gov.bd (Ministry of Agriculture)
- http://services.msw.gov.bd Mministry of social welfare)
- http://services.mincom.gov.bd (Ministry of Commerce)

Junior Software Engineer

Software today LTD Feb 2019 - Jan 2021

My Involvement as software Engineer:

- Developing feature with laravel.
- Solving bug issues.
- Developing some customizations.

Feature Project:

- https://bahokbd.com
- http://admin.quicarbd.com
- http://www.wb-ticket.com
- https://techtodayonline.org

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- PHP, C, C++.
- Laravel, Vue Js, React Js (Basic).
- HTML5, CSS3, bootstrap, JavaScript. jQuery.
- Agile
- MySQL, Redis.
- Apache.
- Amazon AWS (EC2, S3, RDS).
- Github, Gitlab.

EDUCATION

B.Sc in computer science and engineering.

Dhaka International University CGPA(3.63 out of 4.00) (2014-2018)

Diploma in Computer Technology

Cumilla Polytechnic Institute CGPA (3.45 out of 4) (2010-2014)

LEARNING IN PROGRESS:

- AWS Solutions architect.
- Learning React JS

CERTIFICATIONS

- Web Application Development- PHP (BITM)
- Web Development With PHP (Triangle IT Solution)

References

Md. Masud Alom

Zend Certificate Engineer

Founder & author at W3programmers

Senior faculty at PeopleNTech

Email: masud.eden@gmail.com

Cell: +8801716505902